Ryan Acevedo

3100 Inca Street Denver, CO | 501-547-2974 | rymanacevedo@gmail.com | https://github.com/rymanacevedo

Professional Summary

Over 5 years of experience in all sides of Web development and Software Engineering, everything from meeting face to face with clients to discuss having a web presence, personal research and analysis, development, debugging, testing, and implementing applications, as well as a variety of graphic design work. Has been a manager and team lead and knows how to advance and capitalize on opportunities that arise for the market or within the organization. Fun, collaborative team leader with strong problem-solving skills and willingness to adapt and learn from others.

Skills & Abilities

Languages

• JavaScript (Vue.js, Angular, ES6, and Typescript), Java, Python, ASP.NET (C# and .NET Core), and Go

Software

Git, Visual Studio Team Services, Google Cloud, Azure, and Amazon Web Services

Systems

Windows, MacOS, Linux, Windows Server 2008 and 2012, Docker, and Kubernetes

Databases

• SQL Server, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL

Work History

Lead Software Developer

May 2020 - April 2021

Omitron Inc, Colorado Springs, CO

- Focused on user-centered design, building secure Vue.js and Angular apps for the military from the ground up. Several apps which are scalable and still used by the DoD to this day
- Collaborate across fast-paced remote cross-functional teams in order to deliver our products in classified/unclassified environments using Docker/Kubernetes to deploy to enterprise/legacy systems. We worked in language agnostic environments such as C#, Nodejs, Python, and Java
- Contribute to seminars and pair-programming with new developers in order to mentor and train them up to the product team standards. Working with 5 to 7 developers at a time
- Create microservices and APIs built in .NET Core, Spring boot, and NodeJS that can be used across multiple teams and maintain web components that are used for styling across multiple teams

Scientific Research Corporation, Colorado Springs, CO

- Follow user-driven development and basing our user stories around the client's needs
- Build functional SPA in Angular for our users that can be used for their needs within weeks
- Create microservices and APIs built in Spring boot that can be used across multiple teams and maintain web components that are used for styling across multiple teams
- Capitalize on eXtreme Programming (XP) best practices using test driven development (TDD) with Jest and pairing with other developers in order to achieve over eight-five percent code coverage

Software Engineer

December 2018 - November 2019

Lexis Nexis, Colorado Springs, CO

- Develop and design user friendly GUI interfaces for legal editors to highlight paragraphs to train a potential Machine Learning Model in Python
- Suggest automating repetitive build tasks by creating pipelines in Jenkins and migrating to newer technologies such as Git Repos instead of ClearCase
- Drive test driven development (TDD) using JUnit throughout our product teams
- Write up stories in Kanban boards in VersionOne and incorporate RSS feeds for chat bots in our team communications
- Plan and communicate the work breakdown structure for automating legal editors work with a Machine Learning Model

Web Developer/Content Manager

February 2017 - December 2018

National Park College, Hot Springs, AR

- Standardized all web assets and updated web style guide for all sites on np.edu domain using Style
 Dictionary
- Integrated cloud products like Funnelback for site search, Google Cloud for web forms and faculty needs, and Amazon Web Services for video accessibly and translation
- Refactored old code to create event feeds, employee directories, and valuable SPA applications for faculty needs
- Automated main website overhaul to Progressive Web App standards with Webpack and using Vue.js framework
- Test for cross browser compatibility and meet ADA and WCAG requirements for the website
- Discuss with faculty or management on general needs and design inside CMS (OUcampus)

Web Developer

May 2016 - February 2017

Qualified Technology, Hot Springs, AR

- Built a complex product configurator for a large cabinet door shop in WordPress, JavaScript, and MySQL
- Meet with clients to create WordPress websites in under 24 hours with the Genesis Framework
- Write code for websites using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and PHP
- Work with graphics and other designers to determine the website's layout

Volunteering Experience

Peer Tutoring Programming

January 2016 - January 2020

National Park College, Hot Springs, AR

- Reinforce lessons presented by teachers with students one-on-one or in small groups
- Mentor and help students prepare for lessons by getting materials ready or setting up equipment, such as computers, integrated development environments, and compilers
- Depict code reviews in our lessons and teach students real life examples where they would use their code
- Teach in languages such as JavaScript, C#, VBA, and Java

Certifications

- Graduate of Technical Academy for HighEdWeb Association
- Adobe Certified Associate Web Communications
- Microsoft Certified Associate Exam 480
- CompTIA Project+ PK0-004

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Anticipated Graduation: May 2022

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, Utah

- Coursework in data structures, discrete math, algorithms, project management, and capstone
- Studies focused in Software Development in Java and Computer Architecture

Associates of Applied Science with Emphasis in Programming

National Park College, Hot Springs, AR

- Coursework in Android development, SQL Server and database management, and VBA
- Studies focused in ASP.NET, Web Development, and capstone for banking project